keepingcurrentmatters.com 2019-07-03

# Privacy Policy - Keeping Current Matters

### Keeping Current Matters™ Privacy Policy

Last Modified: Feb 21, 2018

At Keeping Current Matters™ we recognize that privacy is extremely important to our members. This Privacy Policy applies to all of the products, services and websites offered by Keeping Current Matters™. This policy may be updated from time to time, so please be sure to reference this document for the most up to date edition of our Privacy Policy.

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, please feel free to [contact us](http://www.keepingcurrentmatters.com/contact/) through our website or write to us at:

**Privacy Policy**  
c/o Keeping Current Matters™  
7204 Glen Forest Drive  
Suite 204  
Richmond, VA 23226

We encourage you to review the entire policy. Please click on any of the links below to review that particular section.

### Information We Collect and How We Use It

In order to provide our full range of services, we may collect the following types of information:

  *     * **Information You Provide** – When you subscribe to Keeping Current MattersTM or any other service that requires registration, we ask you for your personal information (such as your name, email address, company information, and location). For paid services, we also request credit card or other payment account information which we do not maintain and is immediately removed from our servers after payment is processed.  After your order has been placed, your billing account is only referenced by name or auto-generated customer number. Your financial information will never be shared with any entity outside of Keeping Current MattersTM.
    * **Information We Collect Automatically When You Use Our Services**  – In addition to the personal information described above, Keeping Current MattersTM may automatically collect, store and analyze data from your computer or mobile device. Keeping Current MattersTM automatically collects IP addresses and web site usage information when you access our Services, such information includes: the type of browser you use, access times, pages viewed, location, the page you visited before navigating to our platform, information about the computer or mobile device you use to identifiers and mobile network information.  This information helps us evaluate how our visitors and subscribers use and navigate our platform on an aggregate basis, including but not limited to the number and frequency of visitors and subscribers to each web page, and the length of their visits.  Keeping Current MattersTM reserves the right to match your IP address (or any other data) with other data about you in any way permitted by applicable law.
    * **Credit Card Data** – KCM does not store any credit card information on its servers.   Credit card info is taken through our SSL protected web site and then transmitted automatically via API to Infusionsoft to create the order and subscription.   You can view Infusionsoft’s data security information here: <https://www.infusionsoft.com/legal/data-security>.
    * **Cookies** – When you visit Keeping Current Matters™, we may send one or more cookies – a small file containing a string of characters – to your computer or other device that uniquely identifies your browser. We use cookies to improve the quality of our service, including storing user preferences, improving search results and tracking user trends. We may later associate the usage and other information we collect online with personal information about you, as permitted or required by applicable law.  Most web browsers are set to accept cookies by default.  If you prefer, you may be able set your browser to remove or reject all or specific browser cookies.  Please note that if you choose to remove or reject cookies from Keeping Current MattersTM, this could affect the availability, functionality, and the services offered by our platform.
    * **Login Information** – When you access Keeping Current Matters™ services, our servers automatically record information that your browser sends whenever you visit a website. These server logs may include information such as your web request, Internet Protocol address, browser type, browser language, the date and time of your request and one or more cookies that may uniquely identify your browser.
    * **User Communications** – When you send email or other communications to Keeping Current Matters™, we may retain those communications in order to process your inquiries, respond to your requests and improve our services.
    * **Links** – Keeping Current Matters™ may present links in a format that enables us to keep track of whether these links have been followed. We use this information to improve the quality of our services, including customized content and programs.

Keeping Current Matters™ only processes personal information for the purposes described in this Privacy Policy. In addition to the above, such purposes include:

  * Providing enhanced services, including the display of customized content;
  * Research and analysis in order to maintain, protect and improve our services;
  * Ensuring the technical functioning of our network;
  * Protecting the rights of our customers; and
  * Developing new services.

### Retention of Personal Information

Keeping Current MattersTM retains the personal information we receive as described in this Policy for as long as you use our Services or as necessary to fulfill the purposes for which it was collected.  Additionally, Keeping Current MattersTM shall retain such information as necessary to resolve disputes, establish legal defenses, conduct audits, pursue legitimate business purposes, enforce our agreements and comply with applicable laws.

### Choices for Personal Information

When you sign up for a particular service that requires registration, we ask you to provide personal information. If we use this information in a manner different than the purpose for which it was collected, we will ask for your consent prior to such use. If we propose to use personal information for any purposes other than those described in this Privacy Policy, we will offer you an effective way to opt out of the use of personal information for those other purposes. We will not collect or use sensitive information for purposes other than those described in this Privacy Policy, unless we have obtained your prior consent.

Most browsers are initially set up to accept cookies, but you can reset your browser to refuse all cookies or to indicate when a cookie is being sent. However, some features and services may not function properly if your cookies are disabled. You can decline to submit personal information to any of our services, in which case Keeping Current Matters™ may not be able to provide those services to you.

### Information Sharing

Keeping Current Matters™ only shares personal information with other companies or individuals outside of Keeping Current Matters™ in the following limited circumstances:

  *     * We have your consent. We require opt-in consent for the sharing of any sensitive personal information.
    * We provide such information to our subsidiaries, affiliated companies or other trusted businesses or persons for the purpose of processing personal information on our behalf. We require that these parties agree to process such information based on our instructions and in compliance with this Privacy Policy and any other appropriate confidentiality and security measures.

We may share with third parties certain pieces of non-personal information, such as the number of users who searched for a particular term, for example, or downloaded a particular item. Such information does not identify you individually.

It may be necessary − by law, legal process, litigation, and/or requests from public and governmental authorities within or outside your country of residence − for Keeping Current Matters™ to disclose your personal information. We may also disclose information about you if we determine that for purposes of national security, law enforcement, or other issues of public importance, disclosure is necessary or appropriate.

We may also disclose information about you if we determine that disclosure is reasonably necessary to enforce our terms and conditions or to protect the operations of our users. Additionally, in the event of a reorganization, merger, or sale we may transfer any and all personal information we collect to the relevant third party.

### Information Security

Keeping Current Matters™ takes precautions — including administrative, technical, and physical measures — to safeguard your personal information against loss, theft, and misuse, as well as against unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration, and destruction. All information collected, both tangible and electronic, is transmitted securely and appropriate measures are taken to keep it protected from unauthorized access.

Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) encryption is used on all web pages where personal information is collected. To make purchases from these services, you must use an SSL-enabled browser such as Chrome, Safari, Firefox, or Internet Explorer. Doing so protects the confidentiality of your personal information while transmitted over the Internet.

**Data Breach/KCM Protocols:  **In the event of a data breach in our servers, we will use all reasonable efforts to determine what personal data of our customers has been compromised, and notify you of the same as soon as practical. KCM will also notify the appropriate authorities and keep our customers abreast of all developments.

**Where Information is Processed – Your Consent to Processing and Transferring Your Personal Information to the United States:** Keeping Current MattersTM is based in the United States.  If you are visiting from the EU or other regions with laws governing data collection and use, no matter where you are located, you consent to the processing and transferring of your personal information in and to the United States.  The laws of the U.S. governing data collection and use may not be as comprehensive or protective as the laws of the country where you live.  By accessing and using our Services and our platform, you consent that Keeping Current MattersTM may transfer, process, store, use and disclose your data and personal information as described in the Privacy Policy.

### Data Integrity

We review our data collection, storage and processing practices to ensure that we only collect, store and process the personal information needed to provide or improve our services or as otherwise permitted under this Policy. We take reasonable steps to ensure that the personal information we process is accurate, complete, and current, but we depend on our users to update or correct their personal information whenever necessary.

### Accessing and Updating Personal Information

When you use Keeping Current Matters™ services, we provide you with access to your personal information and the ability to correct this data if it is inaccurate or to delete such data if it is not otherwise required to be retained by law or for legitimate business purposes. We provide the details for these procedures in the Support Area of the Keeping Current Matters™ website, or in the footer area of email communication, dependent upon which Keeping Current Matters™ service you are utilizing.

You have the right to demand the erasure of your personal data from our servers.   If you wish to do so, and to stop using our Services, please notify us at [kcmcrew@keepingcurrentmatters.com](mailto:kcmcrew@keepingcurrentmatters.com) and we will do so without undue delay.

### Governing Law/Arbitration

By choosing to visit or utilize the Services or otherwise provide information to us, you agree that any dispute over privacy or the terms of this Privacy Policy will be governed by the laws of the State of New York, and that you agree that any dispute shall be settled by binding arbitration in accordance with the rules of the American Arbitration Association.

### Changes to this Privacy Policy

Please note that this Privacy Policy may change from time to time. We will not reduce your rights under this Privacy Policy without your explicit consent, and we expect most such changes will be minor. Regardless, we will post any Privacy Policy changes on this page and each version of this Privacy Policy will be identified at the top of the page by its effective date, and we will also keep prior versions of this Privacy Policy in an archive for your review.

If you have any additional questions or concerns about this Privacy Policy, please feel free to contact us any time by emailing us at [info@keepingcurrentmatters.com](mailto:info@keepingcurrentmatters.com "info@keepingcurrentmatters.com") or at:

**Privacy Policy**  
c/o Keeping Current Matters™  
7204 Glen Forest Drive  
Suite 204  
Richmond, VA 23226
